Guide to the Cornell Migrant Program campus collection,1953-2006.
Cornell Migrant Program campus collection,1953-2006.
- Series VI. Public Policy
  - Policy Issues in Rural Land Use - ARME, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Legislative Visit (New York State), 1997 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Justice For Farmworkers Campaign (New York State) (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Justice For Farmworkers Campaign Materials (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Lobbying and Hatch Act, 1997-2003 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Fast for Farmworkers (New York State) Labor-Religion Coalition, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Assemblyman Marty Luster's Visit to King Ferry Labor Camp, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Farmers Unions - Articles, 1999-2002 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Farming in New York State, 1999-2002 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - "New York State's Number One Industry is Agriculture (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Public Issues Education, 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 37)
- Series VII. Migrant Education
  - Presentation by John Dunn, Migrant Education, New York State, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Program for the Education of Migratory Children (New York State), 1968 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Speech and Language Program for Migrant Children - Richard T. Haviland, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Statewide Conference on Migrant Education (New York State), 1971 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Monitoring and Evaluation of Summer Workshops for Teachers of Migrant Children - Erik Collins, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Report of Education of Children of Migratory Agricultural Workers (New York State), 1972 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Community Uninvolved Youth Project - Wayne County, NY, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Mattera National Scholarship Fund for Migrant Children (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Parent Tutorial Project (New York State Migrant Education) (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Migrant Youth Programs (New York State Migrant Education) (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Migrant Education Project Summary, 1973-1982 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Bureau of Migrant Education (New York State), 1973-1976 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Delores Allison (Franklin) - Bureau of Migrant Education, 1973-1978 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Paul Reagan, Steve Johnson, 1975-1978 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Special Programs for Children of Migratory Children (United States), 1977 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - State Migrant Education Training (New York State), 1977 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Delores Franklin, 1979-1983 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Richard Bove - Bureau of Migrant Education, 1975-1991 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Sodus (New York) Migrant Summer School, 1974-1977 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Full Swings - Feed Minds (1975 New York State Migrant Education Report), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Proposed Cornell Tutorial Outreach Program (never executed), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Migrant Education Census - Wayne County, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Early Childhood Education - Migrant (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - New York-Florida Teacher Exchange Program, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Migrant Education - Tad Thompson, 1976-1979 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Resources in Migrant Education - Tad Thompson, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Migrant Tutorial Outreach (TOP) (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Tutorial Outreach Programs (TOP) Maps (New York State) (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Education of Migrant Workers' Children - Joseph D. Novak, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Paul R. Fiske/Paul Reagan, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - MERIT (Migrant Education and Recruitment Identification Task), 1981 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Migrant Education Information Update, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Migrant Parents' Rights and Responsibilities (ERIC), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - New York State Migrant Tutorial Outreach Programs 1982 (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - Migrant Education Report, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 36)
  - Migrant Education Report, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 37)
  - Migrant Education Annual Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - Educating the Families that Follow the Crop (New York State), 1985 (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - MENTOR - Harvesting the Harvesters (Curriculum) - Potsdam, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - Dissemination of Migrant Education Programs, 1985-1989 (Box 30, Folder 41)
  - No Student is a Stranger in New York State Schools, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 42)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 43)
  - Cornell Migrant Program - Parenting, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 44)
  - Proposed Legislative Allocation for Migrant Education (New York State), 1987 (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - Institutional Racism Conference, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - State University of New York (SUNY) Tuition Waiver, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Proposal to Transfer of Cornell Migrant Program Projects to CISER, 1987-1988 (Box 30, Folder 48)
  - Stuart J. Mitchell letter to Richard Bove, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 50)
  - Migrant Education Program Policy Manual (U.S.), 1991 (Box 30, Folder 51)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 52)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 53)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 54)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 55)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 56)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 57)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 58)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 59)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 60)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 61)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 62)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 63)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 64)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 65)
  - New York State Migrant Education - Cornell Migrant Program, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 66)
  - Cornell Migrant Education Annual Report, 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 67)
  - Cornell Migrant Education Report (to New York State Migrant Education), 1999-2002 (Box 30, Folder 68)
  - Cornell Migrant Education Report (to New York State Migrant Education), 2002-2003 (Box 30, Folder 69)
  - Cornell Migrant Education Report (Final) - New York State Migrant Education, 2002-2004 (Box 30, Folder 70)
  - State Migrant Education Training (New York State), 2003 (Box 30, Folder 71)
  - Final Migrant Education Report, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 72)
  - New York State Migrant Education Program State Plan, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - New York State Migrant Education Program State Plan (Example), 1984-1991 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Education State Plan, 1990-1993 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - National Conference on Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers (CMP Coordinated), 1990-1991 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Migrant Parent Advisory Council, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Migrant Parent Advisory Council, 1991-1995 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Migrant Parent Advisory Council (New York State), 1996-1999 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Migrant Parent Advisory Council, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - New York State Migrant Parent Advisory Council By-laws and Handbook, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Migrant Parent Advisory Council, 2001-2004 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - National Conference on Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers - Finances, 1990-1991 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Tom Fitzgerald - New York State Education, 1990-1991 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - National Conference on Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers - Conference Materials, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Migrant Education Council (New York State), 1991-1992 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - New York State Migrant Education / A.B.C.D. Cooperation, 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Early Childhood Education - New York State Migrant Education, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Immigrant Students: Their Legal Right of Access to Public Schools, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Migrant Education Evaluations, 1993-1994 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Curriculum Project Proposal (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Translation - Betty Garcia Mathewson, 1996-2001 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - National Forum - Migrant Children and Youth (Interstate Migrant Education Council), 1996 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Even Start - BOCES Geneseo Migrant Center, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Even Start - BOCES Geneseo Migrant Center, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Migrant Youth Councils, 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Even Start - BOCES Geneseo Migrant Center, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Even Start - BOCES Geneseo Migrant Center, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Even Start - BOCES Geneseo Migrant Center, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Even Start - BOCES Geneseo Migrant Center, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Even Start - BOCES Geneseo Migrant Center, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Curriculum and Migrant Farmworkers, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Migrant Students' Poets and Writers Festival - Richard A. Bove Memorial, 1998, 2001, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Education of Mexican Students in New York State, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Portable Assisted Study Sequence (PASS) 1998-99, National Report 2000, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Curriculum on Farm Workers, 2000-2001 (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - Teachers' Guide - New York State Migrant Education Funded - Grades 9-12 (Box 31, Folder 38)
  - Teachers' Guide - New York State Migrant Education Funded - Grades 6-8 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Teachers' Guide - New York State Migrant Education Funded - Grades 2-5 (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 2003 (Box 31, Folder 42)
  - Subseries VIIa. History, Publications
    - New York State Migrant Education - An Historical Brief - Herb Gaige, 1951-1987 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - MEME (National Migrant Newsletter), 1992-1994 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - New York State Migrant Education Directories, 1993-2004 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Migrant Education Pamphlets/Directory - National (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Migrant Education Pamphlets - New York State (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Migrant Education Bibliography - ERIC/CRESS, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - New York State Center for Migrant Studies (Geneseo) Newsletter, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Migrant Education (newsletter), 1975-1977 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Migrant Publications / Tad Thompson, 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Resources in Migrant Education - State Reports, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Migrant Education Communication and Development Office, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Migrant Messages and Consortium Call (New York State), 1980-1987 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Migrant Education - An Annotated Bibliography, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Tutor (New York State), 1983 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Migrant News/Views - Reader Survey, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Migrant Education - ERIC Reports, 1990-2002 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Migrant News and Views (1), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Migrant News and Views (2), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Migrant News and Views (3), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Migrant News and Views (4), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Migrant News and Views (5), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Migrant News and Views (6), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Migrant News and Views (7), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Migrant News and Views (8), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Migrant News and Views (9), 1977-2006 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Eastern Stream Child Abuse Prevention and Education (ESCAPE), 1987 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Migrant Child Abuse Prevention Plans - Maryland, California, Washington, Illinois, Florida, and New Jersey, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Incidence and Patterns of Maltreatment - Migrant Children - NJ, FL, and PA, 1986-1987 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Child Abuse and Neglect, 1979-1985 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - AIDS - Migrant Education, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Evaluation of Migrant Summer School Programs, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Study of Informal Out-of-School Programs with Migrant Children, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Response of Migrant Children to Outdoor Education, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Guidelines for Day Care Programs for Migrant Infants and Toddlers, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Nature Trail Guide - Fair Haven Beach State Park (New York State), 1976 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Toward 2005 (Agricultural Planning), 1985 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Farming for the Future - Sustainable Agriculture and Labor, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Welfare Reform and Agricultural Labor, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Alexandra (Ali) Laks Award, 2007 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Traveling Migrant Exhibit - Tompkins County Museum - Audio Presentations, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Subseries VIIb. Migrant Education Consortium
    - Migrant Education Consortium - Bylaws, 1981, 1985, 1988, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Migrant Education Consortium - Minutes, 1980-07-11-1980-07-13 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Cornell Migrant Program's Acceptance In New York State Migrant Consortium, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Migrant Education Consortium - Minutes, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Migrant Education Consortium - Long-Range Planning, 1983-92 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Basil Dobush (Wayne-Finger Lakes Tutorial Program), 1985 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Migrant Education Consortium - Long-Range Planning, 1985-92 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Migrant Education Consortium - Racism Task Force, 1986-1988 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - New York State Migrant Education Minority Concerns Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Migrant Education Redesign Committee, 1993-1995 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 2002 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Migrant Education Consortium, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Subseries VIIc. Migrant Education Census/MSRTS
    - National Education and Recruitment (Migrant Ed.), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Migrant Education Census (Ages 0-21), 1974-1991 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Migrant Education Census (Ages 0-21), 1992-2003 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Migrant Education Census New York State (Ages 0-21) Example, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Migrant Education Recruitment New York State - Administrator's Guide, 1980-1989 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Migrant Census, Parenting and Community Service (Albany Office), 1981-1982 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Migrant Education Census New York State - Language Other than English, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Migrant Education Recruitment New York State - Recruiter's Manual (Example), 1988 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Migrant Education Census New York State (Ages 0-21) Example, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Migrant Student Record Transfer System (MSRTS), 1973-1976 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - MSRTS - School User Trainer, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - MSRTS and Migrant Identification, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Migrant Student Record Transfer System (MSRTS) Project Report, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Migrant Student Record Transfer System (MSRTS), 1976 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Migrant Student Record Transfer System (MSRTS), 1977-1984 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Migrant Student Record Transfer System (MSRTS) (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - MSRTS - New York State (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - MSRTS Utilization Guide, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - MSRTS - Reporting Skills - Educational (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - MSRTS - Reporting Lists - Health (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - MSRTS - Reporting Lists - Reading Skills, English and Espanol (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - MSRTS - Reporting Lists - Math Skills (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - MSRTS - Reporting Lists - Early Childhood Development and Skills - Ward and Norton (Box 32, Folder 23)
- Series VIII. Migrant Education Studies
  - Educating Migrant Children (New York State), 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Children at the Crossroad (US Dept. HEW), 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "Study of...Problem Solving in Migrant Children" - James O. Schnur, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - "Response of Migrant Children to Outdoor Education" - Thomas L. Hick, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "A Study of Informal Out-of-School Programs with Migrant Children" - David Dik, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Improving Migrant Students' Academic Achievement through Self-Concept Enhancement, 1970-1979 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Sodus (New York State) School Survey - Glenn L. Immegart, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - New York State Migrant Education, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Interstate Migrant Education Task Force - Education Commission of the States, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - An Organizational Design for Migrant Education (NEA), 1977 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Interstate Migrant Education Task Force, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - The Impact of Interstate Programs on Continuity in Migrant Education (ERIC), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Motivating Migrant Secondary Students (ERIC), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Farmworker Youth - The Forgotten Youth, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - "Migrant Education in New York State: An Assessment" - Rellinger and Widmer, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Study of the ESEA Title I Migrant Education Program (RTI), 1981 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Study of Chapter 1 Migrant Education Program (Research Triangle), 1981, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Overview of New York State Migrant Education, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - National Study of Migrant Education (Exotech) (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Migratory Status and School Achievement: Analysis of Critical Mediating Variables, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Current Status of Migrant Education Program (NCLR), 1983 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Migrant Dropout Study (New York State), 1985 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Agricultural Industry Survey - New York State Migrant Education, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Migrant Farmworker Children Interviews - Jane Spring (New York State), 1988 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - "My Migrant Labor Camp School 1949-1961" - Helen Wright Prince (1989), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Homevisiting: A Promising Early Intervention Strategy (GAO), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Transition from School to Work (GAO), 1991 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - "How Much Does Schooling Influence General Intelligence and Its Cognitive Components?" - Stephen J. Ceci, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Coordination of Migrant and Seasonal Farmworker Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - New York (Migrant) Graduation Rate Study (Migrant Youth Programs), 1992 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Invisible Children: A Portrait of Migrant Education in the U.S., 1992 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Rethinking Migrant Education (National Association of State Directors of Migrant Education), 1992 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Falling by the Wayside: Children in Rural America, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - The Oral Histories Collection (Migrant Farmworkers) - Faith Richardson, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Home Literacy Project - Even Start - New York State, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Activities for Early Childhood - Psychomotor Area - Patricia A. Ward (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Activities for Early Childhood - Cognitive Area - Patricia A. Ward (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Activities for Early Childhood - Affective Area - Patricia A. Ward (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Services to Migrant Children (Assessment of the Chapter 1 Program) USDE, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - An Analysis of the Costs of Chapter 1 Migrant Education Program Summer Services, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Elementary School Children - Many Change Schools Frequently, Harming their Education (GAO), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Rethinking Our Classrooms: Teaching for Equity and Justice, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Migrant Children - Education and HHS Need to Improve the Exchange of Participant Information (GAO), 1999 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - "Single Parenthood and School Readiness in White, Black and Hispanic 6- and 7-Year-Olds" - Henry N. Ricciuti, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Coming Up on the Season - Teachers' Resource Guide Grades 2-5 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Coming Up on the Season - Teachers' Resource Guide Grades 6-8 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Coming Up on the Season - Teachers' Resource Guide Grades 9-12 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - "The Environment of Childhood Poverty" - Gary Evans, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Perceptions of Why Migrant Students Dropout of School and What Can Be Done to Encourage Them to Graduate (New York State), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Manual of Practices and Procedures (New York State Migrant Child Care), 1966 (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - Possible Enhancement of Problem-Solving Ability (James O. Schnur), 1970 (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - Children at the Crossroad (Migrant Education, Nutritional), 1970 (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - Statewide Conference on Migrant Education (New York State), 1971 (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - Preschool and Day Care Centers (Bessie Chandler, SUNY Geneseo), 1971 (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - Providing Opportunities (Migrant Education Report - New York State), 1974 (Box 42, Folder 38)
  - Migrant Supplement (New York State Education), 1975 (Box 42, Folder 39)
  - Inside Education (New York State Education Dept.), 1979 (Box 42, Folder 40)
  - Migrant Education '76 (New York State), 1976 (Box 42, Folder 41)
  - Migrant Education (National), 1976 (Box 42, Folder 42)
  - Fill Swings - Feed Minds (Migrant Education Report - New York State), 1975 (Box 42, Folder 43)
  - Seventh Annual Eastern Stream Migrant Education Conference, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 44)
  - Migrant Child Welfare Project (InterAmerica Research Associates), 1976 (Box 42, Folder 45)
  - Special Programs for Children of Migratory Workers (Florida), 1977 (Box 42, Folder 46)
  - "Analysis of...The Title I Migrant Education Program" - National Council of La Raza, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 47)
  - Validation of Student Counts (Research Triangle), 1980 (Box 42, Folder 48)
  - Impact of ESEA Title I Migrant (RTI), 1981 (Box 42, Folder 49)
  - Study of ESEA Title I Migrant Education Program (RTI), 1981 (Box 42, Folder 50)
  - Migrant Education: A Consolidated View, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 51)
  - National Migrant Education Hotline, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 52)
  - Rethinking Migrant Education, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 53)